欢迎光临Air House77超级影院！！！
Welcome to Air House Cinemas
请爱护包厢设施环境卫生
Please take care of the environmental hygiene of the room
如有损坏，照价赔偿
In case of damage ，Compensation at cost
请保管好您的随身物品，以免丢失
Please keep your belongings，So as not to lose
Air House77超级影院祝您观影愉快,每天都有好心情
Air House Cinemas wish you have a nice day! Cinemas wish you have a nice day!
马弘？
Mahiro?
你是马弘 是吗？
You're Mahiro, aren't you?
我是你父亲
I'm your father.
你太年轻了 你可能不记得了
You were so young, you probably don't remember.
我马上就知道是你
I knew it was you right away.
马弘
Mahiro.
你认识我吗？
Do you know me?
-马弘是吗？-是的
- You're Mahiro, right? - Yes.
我们去看樱花吧
Let's go see the cherry blossom.
走吧
Let's go.
樱花在昨天达到了顶峰
The cherry blossom peaked yesterday.
渐渐地 花瓣开始落下
Little by little, the petals have started to fall.
马弘
Mahiro.
你出生后
After you were born...
当你16个月大的时候
when you were about 16 months old...
当我和你在一起的时候
back when I was with you...
你妈妈和我
your mother and I...
我们吵架了
we got in a fight.
不幸的是 我们离婚了
Unfortunately, we got divorced.
一、
I...
我现在有了另一个家庭
I have another family now.
但是
But...
马弘
Mahiro...
你是我的第一个孩子
you were my first child.
事实是
The truth is...
我想每天联系你
I wanted to contact you every day.
然而
However...
因为我现在有了另一个家庭
because I have another family now...
他们告诉我不要联系你
they told me not to contact you.
现在
And now...
你已经12岁了
you've turned 12.
马弘
Mahiro...
你觉得呢 既然我回来了？
What do you think, now that I'm back?
我很高兴你回来了
I'm happy that you came back.
你高兴吗？
You're happy?
你看起来像我
You look like me.
Around here you look like me.
碰巧
Did by any chance...
在学校或任何地方
at school or wherever...
事实上我不在身边
The fact I'm not around...
你的朋友或其他人有说过什么吗？
Did your friends or anyone say anything about that?
总是让我担心
That always worried me.
没事的
It's okay.
真的？
Really?
你很在行
You're good at that.
真的？
Really?
要我帮你拉近点吗？
Should I bring it closer for you?
太棒了！
That's amazing!
马弘 给我照张相
Mahiro, take a picture of me.
怎么样？
How is it?
-很好 -明白了吗？
- Good. - You got it?
看看吧
Take a look.
太好了！
That's nice!
哦 这太好了！
Oh, this is good!
可以 我得到了它
Okay. I got it.
马弘 这边
Mahiro, over here.
我要了
I'm taking it.
那是个好主意
That's a good one.
我们捕捉到了樱花
We captured the cherry blossom.
哦 太好了！看起来我戴着一条花围巾
Oh, that's good! Looks like I'm wearing a flower scarf.
让我带你一个
Let me take one of you.
不 不
No, no.
当然？
Sure?
我想要很多花的照片
I want lots of pictures of the flowers.
我妈妈喜欢樱花
My mom likes cherry blossom.
在这儿怎么样？
How about over here?
抬头看！
Look straight up!
马弘
Mahiro...
-你和你妈妈相处得好吗？-是的
- Do you get along with your mom? - Yes.
-不要打架 对吧？-是的
- No fighting, right? - Right.
见到我你紧张吗？
Were you nervous about meeting me?
-不是真的 -你不是吗？
- Not really. - You weren't?
也许有一点 但我一直很期待
Maybe a little. But I've been looking forward to it.
真的？
Really?
事实上你是
The fact that you were...
勇敢地一个人来
brave enough to come alone...
真的 那是
Really, that was...
鉴于我们已经十年没见面了
Given that we haven't seen each other for ten years...
我没想到你会一个人来这里
I didn't expect you to come here all by yourself.
当我站在那里的时候
When I was standing there,
你用手机给我拍了张照片 是吗？
you took a picture of me with your phone, didn't you?
我马上就知道了
I knew right away.
马弘
Mahiro...
所以事情就是这样
So that's how it is.
他们太棒了！
They're amazing!
你以前去过Yoyogi公园吗？
Have you been to Yoyogi Park before?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
你经常在户外活动 对吧？
You spend a lot of time outdoors, right?
不 我大多呆在家里
No, I mostly stay home.
真的吗？
Seriously?
天气真好
The weather feels great.
是 啊
Yeah.
在Yoyogi公园有很多活动
Quite a lot of action in Yoyogi Park.
下午好
Good afternoon.
石井先生 很高兴再次见到你
Mr. Ishii, how nice to meet you again.
-一定要进来 -谢谢
- Do come in. - Thank you.
请坐
Please take a seat.
谢谢您
Thank you.
我女儿过得怎么样？
How did things go with my daughter?
马弘
Mahiro...
一开始很害羞 你知道吗？
was shy at first, you know?
当然
Of course.
但后来我们去看樱花
But then we went to look at the cherry blossom,
我们四处走动
we walked around,
拍了一些照片
took some pictures...
有些人在玩杂耍
Some guys there were juggling.
我觉得她玩得很开心
I think she had a lot of fun.
哦 我很高兴
Oh, I'm glad.
我可以看一下订单吗？
May I look at the order form?
前进
Go ahead.
啊 她爸爸以前一直玩马
Ah, her father used to play horse all the time.
她记得吗？
Did she remember that?
我问过马弘
I asked Mahiro about it
但她不记得了
but she didn't remember.
哦 我明白了
Oh, I see.
她过去常常骑在他的肩膀上
She used to ride on his shoulders.
那怎么样？
How about that?
我问过她那件事 但她不记得了
I asked her about that but she didn't remember.
也
Also,
马弘的真父亲眼睛抽搐
Mahiro's real father has an eye twitch.
我肯定她会记得的
I was sure she'd remember that.
婴儿真的看父母的眼睛
Infants really look into the eyes of their parents.
是的 我明白了 这样地？
Yes, I see. Like this?
我知道我们要求你提供很多细节
I know we ask you to provide many details.
但我们的政策
But our policy
家庭恋情
at Family Romance
我们只能做真正的自己
is that we can only do what we really are.
所以
So...
比如说 如果我要为马弘抽动眼睛
for example, if I were to twitch my eyes for Mahiro,
看起来我在装模作样
it would look like I was putting on an act.
这是我的看法
That was my opinion.
所以我不想假装
So I didn't want to fake it.
非常感谢你 石井先生
Thank you so much, Mr. Ishii.
请接受这张支票
Please accept this check.
谢谢您
Thank you.
我增加了额外的费用
I've added extra for expenses.
我有食物和杂物的收据
I have the receipts for food and sundries.
我以后可能会带来更多的收据
I may bring more receipts in the future.
非常感谢您今天的光临
Thank you very much for today.
非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
直到下次
Until next time.
中谷夫人
So Mrs. Nakatani.
对
Yes.
这是你们之间的正式合同
This is the official contract between you,
Hikari Nakatani和Family Romance LLC
Hikari Nakatani, and Family Romance, LLC.
事实是
The truth is...
我丈夫病了 身体虚弱
my husband is ill, and his body is weak.
他经常不上班就呆在家里睡觉
He often stays home from work and sleeps.
事实上 我丈夫得了癫痫
The fact is, my husband has epilepsy.
拜托 帮帮我们
Please. Help us.
中谷夫人
Mrs. Nakatani...
这是你的替身丈夫
This will be your stand-in husband.
他真的病了
He's really sick.
所以
So...
这次
this time...
他说他非常想以某种方式在场
he said he desperately wanted to be present somehow.
所以我们想从你这里租个父亲
That's why we wanted to rent a father from you.
请帮帮我们
Please, help us.
你能告诉他你丈夫的名字吗
Would you tell him the name of your husband
好让他排练？
so that he can rehearse?
中田高市
Nakatani Takashi.
他的出生日期？
His date of birth?
1972年10月29日
October 29th, 1972.
你丈夫在家叫什么？
What is your husband called at home?
爸爸
Daddy.
你有宠物吗？
Do you have any pets?
对
Yes.
能告诉我宠物的名字吗？
May I have the pet's name?
我们有一只叫巧克力的狗
We have a dog named Chocolate.
巧克力经常和他说话
Chocolate often talks to him.
她总是知道他的感受
She always knows how he feels.
我可以把她租给你吗？
Shall I rent her to you?
非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
中谷先生
Mr. Nakatani.
请注意记住这一切
Please take care to keep all of this in mind.
当然
Certainly.
我要去见新娘了
I'm going to meet the bride now.
哇 你不是最漂亮的新娘吗！
Wow, aren't you the most beautiful bride!
非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
我是家庭恋情的雇员
I'm an employee of Family Romance.
今天我要做你的父亲
I'll be your father today.
-很高兴认识你 -很高兴做你的
- Glad to make your acquaintance. - Glad to make yours.
这纯粹是巧合 但是
This is purely coincidence but...
我和你父亲同名
I have the same name as your father.
你父亲的名字叫高石 对吗？
Your father's name is Takashi, right?
是的 是的
Yes, it is.
我也是
So is mine.
既然我们即将成为父女
Since we're about to be father and daughter,
我们应该避免使用正式语言
we should avoid formal language.
我刚收到你妈妈的信
I actually just heard from your mother
你父亲患有癫痫
that your father suffers from epilepsy.
那对你来说一定很糟糕
That must be awful for you.
事实上 那不是真的
Actually, that's not true.
他真是个酒鬼
He's really an alcoholic.
是这样吗？
Is that so?
真的很尴尬
It's really embarrassing.
他喝多了没能参加婚礼？
He couldn't make it to the wedding because he gets so drunk?
-是的 就这样 -我明白了
- Yes, that's it. - I see.
真的很尴尬
It's really embarrassing.
那一定是你妈妈撒谎的原因
That must be why your mother lied.
我相信是的
I believe so.
对不起的
Sorry.
但原因是什么并不重要
But it doesn't matter what the reason is.
我今天会照顾好你的父亲
I'll take care of being your father today.
我很高兴我们租了个父亲
I'm so glad we rented a father.
一点问题都没有 我会尽力的
It's no problem at all. I'll do my best.
-谢谢 -放心 不会有事的
- Thank you. - Rest assured, it'll be fine.
我在那边等你
I'll be waiting over there.
做完了 过来
When you're done, come over.
我们会更加了解对方
We'll get to know each other more.
非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
期待很快与您见面
See you soon.
马弘？
Mahiro?
发生了什么？
What's wrong?
你见到你父亲不高兴吗？
Aren't you happy to see your father?
发生了什么？
What's wrong?
别这么伤心
Don't look so sad.
可以
Okay.
坐船怎么样？
How about a boat ride?
好吧 我们走吧
Okay, let's go.
这不是很好吗
Isn't that nice.
你不害怕吧？
You're not scared, are you?
看来我们要淹死了
It looks like we're going to drown.
不 不会发生的
No, it won't happen.
最坏的情况 我们会游泳
Worst case scenario, we'll swim.
我不会游泳
I can't swim.
你不会游泳？
You can't swim?
我会游泳 但不能在脏水里游泳
I can swim, but not in dirty water.
哦 我明白了
Oh, I see.
反正你的腿会累的
Anyway your legs would get tired.
我有点想下车
I kind of want to get off.
继续划！
Just keep paddling!
我们的时间快到了
Our time is nearly up.
马弘
Mahiro...
我们应该发财吗？
Should we get a fortune?
会是一个好的吗？
Is it gonna be a good one?
我要给你读吗？
Should I read it for you?
会怎么样？
What's it gonna be?
哦 太好了！
Oh, nice!
你运气真好！
You got the best fortune!
“你的运气会好起来的 ”
"Your fortune will improve."
“进展将如你所预想的那样 ”
"Progress will be how you envisioned it."
哦 太棒了！
Oh, that's amazing!
“你会遇到特别的人 ”
"You will meet someone special."
“这将是一段持久的关系 ”
"It will be a lasting relationship."
这是关于我们的！
This is about us!
听着
Look.
那么多孤独的人
So many lonesome people.
他们把他们绑在这里
They tie them here
快乐一年
to have happiness for a year.
我们应该一起做吗？
Should we do it together?
让我们把它放在这里
Let's put it right here.
说奶酪！
Say cheese!
最后一枪 好的！
Okay, last shot!
可以
Okay.
谢谢您
Thank you.
哎呀 对不起！
Whoops, sorry!
非常感谢你！
Thank you very much!
真是太棒了
That was amazing.
他也拍了照片！
He took pictures too!
是真的 他做到了
It's true, he did.
那真的很有趣！
That was really fun!
真是个惊喜！
What a surprise!
太神了
Amazing.
马弘意识到我在替你演戏吗？
Did Mahiro realize I was acting for you?
她肯定没有
She definitely didn't.
你看到她的笑容了吗？
Did you see her smile?
她看起来很高兴
She looked so happy.
我付钱给你的事实
The fact that I paid you...
给她一个惊喜
to surprise her...
一切顺利
It went flawlessly.
你的哑剧太棒了
Your pantomiming was terrific.
太棒了 非常完美
Amazing, it went perfectly.
什么风把你吹来了？
What brings you here?
好
Well...
我想和我丈夫离婚
I want to divorce my husband
但他不让我走
but he won't let me go.
我听说这是一个激发变革的好地方
I heard this is a good place to invoke change.
狐狸有改变现实的能力
The Fox has the power to alter reality.
我知道
I know.
人们说我有点像变色龙
People say I'm a bit of a chameleon.
每一天
Every day...
我必须扮演许多不同的角色
I must play many different roles.
有时我想知道
Sometimes I wonder
如果我做了正确的事
if I'm doing the right thing.
我担心被抓
I worry about getting caught.
每天 我都感到不安
Every day, I feel uneasy.
我懂了
I see.
我希望我更像狐狸
I wish I were more like the Fox.
当然
Of course.
祝你好运
Good luck.
马弘
Mahiro.
那孩子是谁？
Who's the kid?
我是艾瑞
This is Airi.
其他的孩子不会和她一起出去的
The other kids won't hang out with her
所以她经常和我在一起
so she often joins me.
-是这样吗 艾瑞？-是的
- Is that so, Airi? - Yeah.
我可以和你一起坐吗？
May I sit with you?
艾瑞？
Airi?
谁给你挑的？
Who picked this out for you?
我妈妈
My mom.
你妈妈？
Your mom?
这些花真可爱
The flowers are really cute.
-这些怎么样？-我妈妈买的
- How about these? - My mom got them.
它们和你的衣服很相配！
They match your dress!
艾瑞！
Airi!
你长大后想做什么？
What do you want to be when you grow up?
一只兔子 长发公主和一名消防队员
A bunny, Rapunzel and a fire fighter.
对吗？
Is that right?
你想做什么都行
You can be anything you want.
其他孩子欺负她
The other kids bully her,
说她在火灾中被烧死了
saying she's been burned in a fire
因为她皮肤黝黑
because she's dark-skinned.
因为其他孩子对她很刻薄
As the other kids are mean to her,
我带她到处走
I take her around with me.
我们为什么不去看看天空树呢？
Why don't we check out the Sky Tree?
让我们？
Shall we?
那边的那个真高！
That's a really tall one over there!
哦 是的！
Oh yeah!
这是一座高楼 好吧！
It's a tall building alright!
看 火车来了！
Look, there's a train coming!
那是什么颜色的火车？
What color train is that?
橙色
Orange.
这是正确的
That's right.
看这边
Look this way.
有一个直升机平台
There's a helicopter platform.
在那边 你看到了吗？
Over there, can you see it?
我想让你给她一个拥抱
Airi wants you to give her a hug.
我们拥抱一下好吗？
Shall we hug?
你害羞吗？
Are you shy?
你不是吗？
You're not?
我也可以拥抱一下吗？
Can I have a hug too?
许个愿
Make a wish.
你赢了多少钱？
So, how much did you win?
两千万日元（18万美元）
Twenty million yen ($180,000).
两千万日元！
Twenty million yen!
对
Yes.
太不可思议了
That's incredible.
你赢了那么多？
You won that much?
太不可思议了
That's unbelievable.
两千万日元！
Twenty million yen!
那么 你赢之前发生了什么？
So, what happened before you won?
在那之前
Up until then...
没有什么好事发生在我身上
nothing good ever really happened to me.
那是最美妙的时刻
That was the single most amazing moment
在我的一生中
in my entire life.
你赢的时候发生了什么？
What happened when you won?
有人来找我
Someone came to my door.
我被要求出示身份证
I was asked for my identification.
当我给他们看我的身份证时
When I showed them my ID,
我发现我是赢家
I found out I was a winner
这是我有生以来第一次
for the first time in my life.
我很震惊
I was shocked.
我变白了
I turned white.
我想是的
I would imagine so.
我不知道这是怎么回事
I had no idea that's how it works.
我能帮你什么忙吗？
Is there anything I can do to help you?
好
Well...
我赢了以后
after I won,
我觉得我想再次拥有那种感觉
I felt like I wanted to have that feeling again.
所以我买了成百上千的票
So I've been buying hundreds, thousands of tickets.
我有生之年可能不会再赢了
I might not win again in my lifetime
但我总是希望好运能回到我身边
but I always hope luck may return to me.
可能需要100年
It might take 100 years
但我一直在买票
but I keep buying tickets.
是这样吗？
Is that so?
如果是这样的话
If that's the case...
我想我能帮你
I think I can help you.
这绝对是个惊喜
It will be a total surprise.
听起来怎么样？
How does that sound?
是的 请
Yes, please.
我们可以做吗？
Shall we do it?
好吧
Okay then.
国家铁路系统
The National Train System.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你知道你对它做了什么吗？
You realize what you did to it?
你明白 不是吗？
You understand, don't you?
如果火车晚点超过50秒
If a train is more than 50 seconds late,
它会对整个系统产生连锁反应
it has a knock-on effect on the entire system.
但你提前20秒释放了火车
But you released the train 20 seconds early.
你觉得发生了什么事？
What do you think happened?
如果火车晚点了 我们还是没事的
If the train is a little late, we're still okay.
事实上 提前离开要糟糕得多
In reality, an early departure is far worse.
你让火车提前20秒发车
You let the train leave 20 seconds early.
你怎么能允许这样？
How could you allow that?
当那件事发生的时候
When that happened...
那列火车上有孩子
There were children on that train.
他们被困在里面
They got trapped inside.
父母出去装行李
Parents went out to load their luggage
火车一个人带着孩子们走了！
and the train took off with the kids alone!
这不是问题吗？
Is that not a problem?
这个巨大的错误
This monumental mistake
把我们带到了出版业
led us to publishing
每家报纸上都有一整版的道歉
a full-page apology in every newspaper.
我们不得不正式道歉！
We had to issue a formal apology!
你到底在想什么？
What the hell were you thinking?
你在想什么？
What were you thinking?
好吗？从现在开始
Alright? From now on,
你要认真对待你的工作！
you need to take your fucking job more seriously!
别这么傻！
Don't be such a moron!
好吧
Alright.
够了
That's enough.
我在看着你
I'm watching you.
石井 太谢谢你了 你救了我
Ishii, thank you so much. You saved me.
你真的替我承担了责任
You really took the blame for me.
我应该多说几句吗？
Should I have said more?
你很好
You were fine.
多亏了你 我会没事的
Thanks to you, I'll be okay.
不客气
You're welcome.
我来承担责任
With me taking the blame,
我想他们会放你鸽子的
I think they'll let you off for this.
真的 非常感谢
Really, thank you so much.
没事的
It's okay.
幸好他们让你逍遥法外
Good thing they let you get away with it.
他真的很生气 不是吗？
He was really mad, wasn't he?
这对我的家庭很重要
This was really important to my family.
你的校服很好看
Your school uniform looks great.
非常感谢你
Thank you very much.
我们买了全新的
We bought it brand new.
从现在开始我要穿它
I'm going to wear it from now on.
马弘 你真的长大了
Mahiro, you're really growing up.
你穿起来真好看
It looks really good on you.
谢谢您
Thank you.
有点大 但是
It's a little bit big, but...
可能是
Could it be...
你穿着它只是为了给我看？
that you're wearing it just to show me?
谢谢您
Thank you.
听着 这是我为你做的
Look, I made this for you.
那太好了！
That's great!
我会好好照顾它的
I'll take good care of it.
它很精致 所以要小心
It's delicate, so be careful.
还有 我画画 这是一个旧的
Also, I draw pictures. This is an old one.
我想捕捉运动
I wanted to capture movement.
太详细了！
That's so detailed!
你有小时候的照片吗？
Do you have pictures from when you were little?
我愿意！
I do!
我能看看吗？
Could I see?
这样地？
Like this?
哇 真可爱！你多大了？
Wow, that's cute! How old were you?
大约三点
About three.
你太时髦了
You're so fashionable.
我妈妈都给我买的
My mom bought it all for me.
还有其他人吗？
Any others?
嗯 这个怎么样？
Um, what about this?
可爱的！
Cute!
在当地一家咖啡馆
It's at a local cafe.
你看起来像个模特
You look like a model.
那是个瑜伽姿势！
That's a yoga pose!
它真的很漂亮
It's really beautiful.
-它被带到哪里去了？-巴厘岛
- Where was it taken? - Bali.
巴厘岛？
Bali?
在巴厘岛的海滩上 它很漂亮
At a beach in Bali. It was beautiful.
真正地？那里的海洋太美了
Really? The ocean's so beautiful there.
天气也很好
The weather was nice too.
只是天很热 我被晒伤了
Except it was hot, I got sunburned.
我很嫉妒 这么漂亮的地方
I'm jealous, such a beautiful place.
马弘说过我吗？
Did Mahiro say anything about me?
有什么重要的事我应该知道吗？
Anything important I should know about?
Mahiro有一个Instagram账户 不是吗？
Mahiro has an Instagram account, doesn't she?
对
Yes.
她真的想控制自己的Instagram
She really wants control of her own Instagram.
但你说这不好
But you said it wasn't okay.
一、
I...
我想你可以给她更多的自由
I think you could give her more freedom.
但她才12岁
But she's only 12 years old.
互联网上有很多危险的人
There are lots of dangerous people on the Internet.
作为一个单身母亲
As a single mother,
我得多保护我的孩子
I have to protect my child more.
早些时候她给我看了她的Instagram
Earlier she showed me her Instagram.
例如
For example...
她在巴厘岛做瑜伽姿势 像这样
where she's doing a yoga pose, like this, in Bali.
巴厘岛？
Bali?
是的 巴厘岛
Yes, Bali.
我不觉得有什么问题
I just don't see the problem
她贴了这样的照片
with her posting pictures like that.
但我们从没去过巴厘岛
But we've never been to Bali.
但她说她摆姿势
But she said she posed...
就像在巴厘岛的海滩上
like this on a beach in Bali.
我记得那个海滩
I remember that beach
但那只是一个当地的海滩
but it was just a local beach.
-本地的？-是的
- Local? - Yeah.
我从没带她去巴厘岛
I've never taken her to Bali.
我给她拍了那张照片 但只是在附近的海滩上
I took that picture of her but it was just at a nearby beach.
她是这么说的吗？
Is that what she said?
马弘说是在巴厘岛
Mahiro did say it was in Bali.
她为什么要说那样的话？
Why would she say something like that?
我懂了
I see.
马弘想让她父亲看看
Mahiro wanted to show her father
她的生活很有趣
that her life was interesting.
我在骗马弘
I'm lying to Mahiro.
但马弘也在骗我
But Mahiro is also lying to me.
我们都在骗对方
We're both lying to each other.
就这样
And that's that.
下午好 我是电力公司的
Good afternoon, I'm with the electric company.
抱歉打扰你了
Sorry to bother you.
你有空吗？
Do you have a moment?
我们在这一带做些工作
We're doing some work in the area,
安装光纤
installing fiber optics.
更多信息
For more information,
你可以看一下这份文件
you can look through this document.
如果你同意
If you agree to it,
我们只需要你在下面签名
we just need your signature at the bottom.
就在这里
Right here.
如果你愿意的话
If you please.
你能重复你的名字吗？
Can you repeat your name for me?
长池清原
Kiyohara Nagiko.
再大声一点
Again, a little louder.
长池清原
Kiyohara Nagiko.
长池清原？
Kiyohara Nagiko?
对
Yes.
长池清原？
Kiyohara Nagiko?
你是说长谷清原吗？
Did you say Kiyohara Nagiko?
祝贺 你！
Congratulations!
你真的做到了！你赢了！
You really did it! You won!
真的 你赢了2000万日元！
It's true, you won 20,000,000 yen!
你做到了 你赢了！
You did it, you won!
你做到了！
You did it!
你赢了2000万日元！
You won 20,000,000 yen!
你做到了！
You did it!
这不是梦 你真的赢了！
It's not a dream, you really won!
你打算把钱花在什么上面？
What are you going to spend it on?
你真幸运！
You're so lucky!
你做到了！
You did it!
抱歉让你久等了 这是甜心派
Sorry to keep you waiting. This is Sweetie Pie.
他很可爱！
He's cute!
我来告诉你怎么对付刺猬
Let me tell you how to handle a hedgehog.
刺猬的肚子很软
Hedgehogs have very soft bellies.
这是不会伤害你的一面
This is the side that won't hurt you.
如果你像这样按摩甜饼 他很可爱
If you massage Sweetie Pie like this, he's very cute.
你用镊子喂他
You use these tweezers to feed him.
如果你够勇敢 你也可以用你的手
If you're brave enough, you can also use your hands.
石井先生 非常感谢你今天把大家聚集在这里
Mr. Ishii, thank you so much for gathering everyone here today.
我们看起来很专业
We look like pros.
你看起来真像书呆子
You really look like nerds.
所以
So...
如果今天的照片很受欢迎 我会很出名的
If today's photos are a hit, I'll become so famous.
我会成为明星的！
I'll be a star!
我的未来掌握在你手中
My future is in your hands.
当所有人看到狗仔队时
When everyone sees all the paparazzi,
我会在社交媒体上疯传的
I'll go viral on social media.
我要你抓住我好的一面 左边
I want you to capture my good side, the left.
确保我看起来很可爱 好吗？
Make sure I look cute, alright?
你 石井 我要你从后面拍视频
And you, Ishii, I want you to shoot video from behind.
好吧 苏美
Okay, Sumi.
确保狗仔队在镜头里
Make sure the paparazzi are in the shot.
我会看起来像个名人
I'll look like a celebrity.
-非常重要 -没错
- Very important. - Exactly.
我不会让你失望的
I won't let you down.
让我看起来不错
Make me look good.
-我们来吧！-好了 我们走！
- Let's do this! - Okay, let's go!
阴凉处比较凉快
It's cooler in the shade.
那边有海龟
There are turtles over there.
你想去看看吗？
Do you want to go look?
发生了什么？
What's wrong?
有什么事困扰你吗？
Is something bothering you?
你想告诉我吗？
Do you want to try telling me?
如果你想的话 你可以小声说
You can whisper it if you want.
在我的班上
In my class...
我喜欢一个男孩
there's a boy I like.
但他根本没注意到我
But he doesn't notice me at all.
好像我根本不存在
It's like I don't even exist.
很难接受
It's hard to take.
学校里有个你喜欢的男孩？
So there's a boy at school you like?
孩子们
Boys...
很难注意到女孩的感受
are slow to notice how girls feel.
他们忙着玩
They're too busy playing.
他们就这么想
That's all they think about.
你知道我的意思吗？
You know what I mean?
当我遇到你妈妈的时候
When I met your mother...
一开始 我根本没注意到她的感受
at first, I didn't notice her feelings at all.
她真的很难过
She was really upset.
但是
But...
最后
in the end...
我娶了你妈妈
I married your mother.
不会有事的
It's going to be okay.
马弘 你才12岁
Mahiro, you're only 12.
你到了一个年龄
You're coming to an age...
从现在开始
where from now on
你会经历很多心痛
you're going to experience a lot of heartache.
有时候 我们都是隐形的
Sometimes, we are all invisible.
欢迎来到亨纳酒店
Welcome to the Henn Na hotel.
请使用触摸面板选择您的语言
Please use the touch panel to select your language.
-很高兴认识你 -我也很高兴认识你
- Nice to meet you. - Very nice to meet you too.
我的事业叫做家庭
My business is called Family Romance.
我们专门雇佣家庭成员
We specialize in hiring out family members,
雇佣朋友
hiring out friends,
无论客户喜欢什么
whichever the client prefers.
基本上 我们提供人来满足客户的愿望
Basically, we provide people to fulfill the client's wishes.
这就是我经营的公司类型
That's the type of company I run.
但我对你们的机器人旅馆很感兴趣
But I'm interested in your robot hotel
看看我们能不能在某种程度上
to see if we can use, to some degree,
我们自己的企业里的机器人
robotics in our own business.
我想听听你是怎么创办机器人旅馆的
I wanted to hear about how you started the robot hotel.
机器人的用途
The purpose of robots
提升客户体验
is to enhance customer experience.
他们不仅仅是为了帮助人们
They're not just to assist people,
这也是为客户创造一个娱乐的世界
it's also about creating a world of entertainment for the customer.
这就是这家酒店的理念
That's the concept of this hotel.
人类机器人就是这样
It's the case for the human robots
但我们也有鱼机器人
but we also have fish robots.
鱼机器人在这里纯粹是
The fish robots are here purely
招待我们的顾客
to entertain our customers.
在未来 你认为他们会有梦想吗？
In the future, do you think they will have dreams?
不可能知道
It is impossible to know
他们的想法
what is in their minds.
按一下按钮 说出你的名字
Press the button and say your name.
石井由一
Ishii Yuichi.
下午好 今天好吗？
Good afternoon, how are you today?
按一下按钮 说出你的名字
Press the button and say your name.
朱坤 我的朋友
Ju-kun, my friend.
我最近睡不着觉
I haven't been able to sleep lately.
不久前 我在公园
A while ago, I was at the park,
武士们用剑练习的地方
where samurai were practicing with swords.
-哦 像是表演？-是的 没错
- Oh, like a performance? - Yeah, exactly.
但在我的梦里
In my dream, though,
他们没有剑
they didn't have swords
但却在进行仪式性的自杀
but were committing ritual suicide.
所以在你的梦里 人们犯了seppuku
So in your dream, people are committing seppuku
但是没有剑吗？
but have no swords?
是 啊
Yeah.
还在死去
And still dying.
最初 他们有假剑
Originally, they had fake swords
但在我的噩梦中 根本没有剑
but in my nightmare, there are no swords at all.
这是相当宽敞的
This is quite spacious.
是的 这是我们的大房间
Yes, this is our larger room
但取决于哀悼者的数量
but depending on the number of mourners,
我们可以改变尺寸
we can change the size.
我们也可以安排一个小组
We can arrange for a small group as well.
如果您愿意的话 我们还有这个小一点的
We also have this smaller one, if you prefer.
至于后面的祭坛
As for the altar back here,
我们有这个大的
we have this large one.
我可以看看这个棺材吗？
May I see this coffin?
是的 在这里
Yes, over here.
它有多大？
How large is it?
这具棺材长180厘米
This coffin is 180cm long.
我需要185厘米
I'll need 185cm.
我们的尺寸可达210厘米
We have sizes up to 210cm.
对于一个185厘米高的男性来说 这个会不会太紧了？
Would this one be too tight for a 185cm tall male?
对
Yes.
如果有人在呼吸
If a body was breathing,
有人能注意到吗？
would anyone be able to notice?
这通常不会发生
That doesn't usually happen.
最近
Recently,
人们一直在寻找经验
people have been seeking the experience
死而不死
of being dead without dying.
这几乎成了一种趋势
It's almost becoming a trend.
你能看见有人在这里哭吗？
Would you be able to see someone crying in here?
在那里 你的情绪会隐藏起来
Deep in there, your emotions would be hidden.
有可能进去吗？
Is it possible to get inside?
是的 我们可以为您准备
Yes, we can prepare it for you.
你想试试吗？
Would you like to try it out?
是的 当然
Yes, absolutely.
那样的话 我会为你安排的
In that case, I'll have it set up for you.
如果你不介意的话 请脱下你的鞋
Please take off your shoes, if you don't mind.
我可以吗？
May I?
这里很安静
It's very quiet in here.
在你的坟墓里 一切都是沉默
In your grave, it's all silence.
谢谢你和我一起去看神谕
Thank you for coming with me to see the Oracle.
我一个人感到孤独
I was feeling lonesome by myself,
所以我很高兴有一个可以信任的朋友
so I'm glad to have a friend I can trust.
这就是你要付出的代价
It's what you're paying for.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
我觉得马弘有男朋友了
I have a feeling that Mahiro has a boyfriend.
你听到什么了吗？
Have you heard anything?
-马弘？-是的
- Mahiro? - Yeah.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
我什么也没听说过
I've heard nothing about that.
你能召唤灵魂吗
Are you able to invoke the spirit
我前夫的？
of my previous husband?
他叫什么名字？
What's his name?
我丈夫的名字叫太一
My husband's name was Taiichi.
你一个人住吗？
Are you living alone?
我有一个女儿
I have a daughter.
哦 太好了
Oh, that's good.
从现在开始
From now on,
你一定要坚强
you must be strong...
对你很重要的人
for someone important to you.
在你的精神之旅中
On your spiritual voyage,
勇往直前
forge ahead
找到你真正的幸福
and find your true happiness.
至于你的孩子
As for your child...
她应该住在国外的某个地方
she should live somewhere overseas.
我宁愿你知道
I know you would rather
她住在离你很近的地方
she lived somewhere close to you.
拜托
Please...
这就是我想告诉你的
That's what I wanted to tell you.
一年之内 哪怕只有一次
In the span of a year, even if only once
在亡灵节期间
during the Festival of the Dead...
在此期间
During that time,
你应该向你的祖先祈祷
you should pray to your ancestors.
为你需要的东西祈祷
Pray for the things you need
你很感激
and that you are grateful for.
到了阴间
Reaching for the Netherworld,
我希望你有很多有意义的时刻
I hope you have lots of meaningful moments,
幸福
happiness,
还有感激之情
and gratitude.
我很高兴 谢谢您
It has been a pleasure. Thank you.
谢谢您
Thank you.
我们的会议到此结束
This concludes our session.
你跟死人说话了吗？
Did you speak with someone dead?
不
No.
我试着联系一个活着的人
I tried instead to reach someone alive.
一个活着的人？
A living person?
马弘 我们骑那辆吧！
Mahiro, let's ride that one!
看起来很有趣！
It looks like fun!
我求你了！
I'm begging you!
一个人骑
Ride it alone.
为什么？你爸爸想骑它！
Why? Your dad wants to ride it!
你应该一起来！
You should come along!
看起来很有趣！
It looks like so much fun!
不会有事的！
It'll be fine!
没有机会
Not a chance.
我要吐了
I'll throw up.
你会害怕的
You can be scared.
我不害怕！
I'm not scared!
但我会吐的
But I'll throw up.
最近 马弘一直在说
Recently, Mahiro has been saying
她爱我
that she loves me.
前几天
The other day,
我和马弘在一个摄影棚里照相
Mahiro and I took pictures in a booth.
看看这些心
Look at all these hearts.
马弘说
Mahiro said...
她想永远和我在一起
she wants to be with me forever.
在周末 她想和我呆在一起
On the weekends, she wants to stay with me.
她说她几乎不占地方
She says she'd barely take up any space.
我们需要面对事实
We need to face facts.
这太过分了 不是吗？
This is going too far, isn't it?
如果我们继续
If we carry on...
在家庭恋情
At Family Romance...
我们不允许去爱
we are not allowed to love
被爱或被爱
or to be loved.
所以
So...
我需要更加小心
I need to be more careful.
你就不能和我们一起住吗？
Can't you just come live with us?
我很高兴听到
I'm happy to hear that...
但我做不到
but that I cannot do.
这是客厅 在那边 厨房
This is the living room. Over there, the kitchen.
你可以全部使用
You can use it all.
这是一个很好的提议
That's a lovely offer...
但我真的不应该
but I really shouldn't.
这里也有游泳池
There's a pool here too.
一起游泳就好了
It would be nice to swim together.
我想我们可以成为一个真正的家庭
I think we could become a real family.
这就是马弘的房间
This is what Mahiro's room looks like.
如此整洁
So tidy.
这是我的房间
This is my room.
你可以在这里用任何你喜欢的东西
You can use anything you like in here.
你为什么不看看会是什么感觉？
Why don't you see what it would feel like?
我想
I think...
我们不应该再这样下去了
we shouldn't continue this.
不是更好
Wouldn't it be better...
如果我死了？
if I died?
前几天 我去了一家殡仪馆
The other day, I visited a funeral home.
所以
So...
这次
this time...
你应该租一个死人
you should rent a death.
我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
一、
I...
我不能这么做
I can't do this.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
谢谢你所做的一切
Thank you for everything.
我能说什么？
What can I say?
我觉得你的工作
I think the work you're doing
真的很棒
is really great.
你让很多人都很开心
You're making a lot of people really happy.
家庭浪漫是令人钦佩的
Family Romance is admirable.
我认为这是一家令人难以置信的公司
I think it's an incredible company.
你制造了幻觉
You create illusions
创造生活
to make the lives
你的客户更好
of your clients better.
那会让你感觉很好
That should make you feel good.
这真的很值得称赞 不是吗？
That's really praiseworthy, isn't it?
你知道的
You know...
有时候 我想
sometimes, I wonder...
不管我自己的家人
whether my own family...
可能被人雇了
might have been hired by someone.
如果他们只是
What if they are just...
演员扮演角色？
actors playing roles?
字幕：HIVENTY
Subtitling: HIVENTY
沃纳 非常感谢你在放映结束后加入我们讨论这部电影
Werner, thank you so much for joining us after the screening to discuss the film.